export const chapter = "Chapter - 5: The Sultanate Period : Regional Kingdoms ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "During the medieval period in India, why can it be considered a fallacy to think that the Delhi sultans ruled over the whole of India?",
        optionA:
          "Different regions were constantly under the control of Delhi sultans.",
        optionB: "There were multiple Hindu kingdoms that existed.",
        optionC:
          "The sultans were not interested in ruling the entire country.",
        correctAnswer: "B) There were multiple Hindu kingdoms that existed.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was the influence of Hindu kingdoms during the medieval period in India?",
        optionA: "Hindu kingdoms became non-existent.",
        optionB: "Hindu influence shrank but remained significant.",
        optionC: "Hindu influence dominated the entire country.",
        correctAnswer: "B) Hindu influence shrank but remained significant.",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is an important regional kingdom mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "Mughal Empire",
        optionB: "Vijayanagara Kingdom",
        optionC: "Ottoman Empire",
        correctAnswer: "B) Vijayanagara Kingdom",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Who is known for helping Hindus resettle in Kashmir and restoring destroyed temples?",
        optionA: "Rana Sanga",
        optionB: "Zainul Abidin",
        optionC: "Krishnadeva Raya",
        correctAnswer: "B) Zainul Abidin",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which regional kingdom is known for its valiant ruler Rana Sanga?",
        optionA: "Mewar",
        optionB: "Malwa",
        optionC: "Bengal",
        correctAnswer: "A) Mewar",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What were the two main sources of revenue in regional kingdoms during the medieval period in India?",
        optionA: "Trade and industry",
        optionB: "Agriculture and land",
        optionC: "Tax on non-Muslims and trade",
        correctAnswer: "B) Agriculture and land",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was jaziya in the context of regional kingdoms during the medieval period?",
        optionA: "A tax on trade",
        optionB: "A tax on landowners",
        optionC: "A tax on non-Muslims",
        correctAnswer: "C) A tax on non-Muslims",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which regional kingdom is known for its famous Vithalaswami Temple?",
        optionA: "Malwa",
        optionB: "Marwar",
        optionC: "Vijayanagara",
        correctAnswer: "C) Vijayanagara",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What were the main departments of administration in regional kingdoms?",
        optionA: "Revenue and trade",
        optionB: "Military and agriculture",
        optionC: "Revenue, military, and royal affairs",
        correctAnswer: "C) Revenue, military, and royal affairs",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What was encouraged in regional kingdoms to contribute to culture and art development?",
        optionA: "Taxation",
        optionB: "Craftsmanship",
        optionC: "Trade",
        correctAnswer: "B) Craftsmanship",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "During the medieval period in India, the entire country never came under the control of __________ ruler.",
        options: {
          A: "a single",
          B: "multiple",
          C: "a powerful",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) a single",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The medieval period in India is sometimes described as the Muslim period, but the text suggests that this description is far from the ________.",
        options: {
          A: "truth",
          B: "reality",
          C: "understanding",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) truth",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In the regional kingdoms, the administration was divided into departments, with the important ones being revenue, military, and ________ affairs.",
        options: {
          A: "economic",
          B: "administrative",
          C: "royal",
        },
        correctAnswer: "C) royal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Two main sources of revenue in the regional kingdoms were ________ and trade.",
        options: {
          A: "agriculture",
          B: "land",
          C: "industry",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) land",
      },
      {
        question: "Some Muslim rulers levied ________ as a tax on non-Muslims.",
        options: {
          A: "jaziya",
          B: "property tax",
          C: "sales tax",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) jaziya",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Krishnadeva Raya is considered the ablest of all rulers in the regional kingdoms due to his valiant fighting, administrative skills, and keen interest in ________.",
        options: {
          A: "trade",
          B: "literature",
          C: "military tactics",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) literature",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rajput rulers in Mewar and Marwar set new tales of ________ and bravery.",
        options: {
          A: "trade",
          B: "courage",
          C: "artistry",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) courage",
      },
      {
        question:
          "One of the important books mentioned in the text is the Mitakshara by ________.",
        options: {
          A: "Krishnadeva Raya",
          B: "Vijnaneswara",
          C: "Zainul Abidin",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) Vijnaneswara",
      },
      {
        question:
          "A number of buildings, temples, forts, and mosques were built during this period, including the Vithalaswami Temple in the ________ kingdom.",
        options: {
          A: "Mewar",
          B: "Vijayanagara",
          C: "Malwa",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) Vijayanagara",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The ruler in regional kingdoms kept a major part of the army under his direct control, while he also assigned troops to his ________.",
        options: {
          A: "ministers",
          B: "landlords",
          C: "relatives",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) landlords",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The Delhi sultans ruled over the entire country during the medieval period.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Regional kingdoms during the medieval period in India had their own sources of revenue, including land and trade.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Hindu influence in India expanded during the medieval period.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The administration in regional kingdoms was mainly centered around the ruler.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Jaziya was a tax levied on Muslims in the regional kingdoms.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Krishnadeva Raya was known for his administrative skills but had no interest in literature.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Rajput rulers in Mewar and Marwar were known for their courage and bravery.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal societies in India were heavily influenced by British colonial rule.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British introduced forest laws to preserve and protect the tribal way of life.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "B) False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Tribal revolts occurred when the British attempted to intrude into the tribal way of life.",
        options: {
          A: "True",
          B: "False",
        },
        correctAnswer: "A) True",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
